<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sam writes</title>
    <link>http://samueltho.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sam writes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://samueltho.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The pros and cons of a discovery week</title>
      <link>http://samueltho.github.io/post/to_discover_or_not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samueltho.github.io/post/to_discover_or_not/</guid>
      <description>Reflections on discoveries I was recently chatting to someone in my team and we spent a few moments discussing how we had not had a team &amp;ldquo;kick off&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;inception&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; week for the product/initiative we were working on. This got me thinking about how incredible achievement it was that we had managed to align as a team and start building something new from the ground up all within a few days.
In this case it was quite easy not to have an extensive discovery week: the problem we were needing to solve was in essence handed to us - our team is building some services and algorithms that connect to something much bigger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned about climbing, not climbing, in 2020</title>
      <link>http://samueltho.github.io/post/lockdown_climbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samueltho.github.io/post/lockdown_climbing/</guid>
      <description>Living with restrictions I live in Barcelona which had quite a strict lockdown during 2020. Since the summer there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been another lockdown but there have been lots of restrictions (de-facto lockdown) at various times. These restrictions have on-off closed climbing gyms and travel bans have made climbing outdoors not possible. I wanted to reflect a bit on how the last year impacted my climbing.
Training did me a lot of good&amp;hellip; Overall I think the restrictions actually helped me be a much better climber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting time to build a feature using Jira and R</title>
      <link>http://samueltho.github.io/post/project_forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samueltho.github.io/post/project_forecasting/</guid>
      <description>The problem I recently found myself in a position where I needed to forecast when an upcoming feature our team was about to start working on would be completed. Until that point we had quite happily been building without estimating the size of the work we were getting through. I was keen to not rely on any gut feelings to figure this out. Fortunately by this point we had a been working together for some time, so we had enough data to be able to help make a forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
